<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Philip Kindred Dick</string>

    <string name="basic_info">
        Philip Kindred Dick (December 16, 1928 – March 2, 1982) was an American writer known for
        his work in science fiction. His work explored philosophical, social, and political themes,
        with stories dominated by monopolistic corporations, alternative universes, authoritarian
        governments, and altered states of consciousness. His writing also reflected his interest
        in metaphysics and theology, and often drew upon his life experiences, addressing the
        nature of reality, identity, drug abuse, schizophrenia, and transcendental experiences.
        Dick produced 44 published novels and approximately 121 short stories, most of which
        appeared in science fiction magazines during his lifetime.
        \n\tBorn in Chicago, Illinois, Dick moved to the San Francisco Bay Area with his family at
        a young age. He began publishing science fiction stories in 1951, at the age of 22.
        His stories initially found little commercial success,[2] but his 1962 alternative history
        novel The Man in the High Castle earned Dick early acclaim, including a Hugo Award for Best
        Novel. He followed with science fiction novels such as Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?
        (1968) and Ubik (1969). His 1974 novel Flow My Tears, the Policeman Said won theJohn W.
        Campbell Memorial Award for Best Science Fiction Novel. Following a series of paranormal
        experiences in February 1974, Dick\'s work engaged more explicitly with issues of theology,
        philosophy, and the nature of reality, as in novels A Scanner Darkly (1977) and VALIS
        (1981). A collection of his nonfiction writing on these themes was published posthumously
        as The Exegesis of Philip K. Dick (2011). He died in 1982 in Santa Ana, California, at the
        age of 53, due to complications from a stroke.
        \n\tA variety of popular Hollywood films based on Dick\'s works have been produced, including
        Blade Runner (1982), Total Recall (adapted twice: in 1990 and in 2012), Minority Report
        (2002), A Scanner Darkly (2006), and The Adjustment Bureau (2011). Meanwhile, the novel
        The Man in the High Castle (1962) was made into a multi-season television series by Amazon,
        starting in 2015.
        \n\tIn 2005, Time magazine named Ubik (1969) one of the hundred greatest English-language
        novels published since 1923. In 2007, Dick became the first science fiction writer ever
        to be included in The Library of America series.
    </string>

    <string name="biography">
        \tEarly life\n\t
        Philip Kindred Dick and his twin sister, Jane Charlotte Dick, were born six weeks
        prematurely on December 16, 1928, in Chicago, Illinois, to Dorothy (née Kindred; 1900–1978)
        and Joseph Edgar Dick (1899–1985), who worked for the United States Department of
        Agriculture. His paternal grandparents were Irish.[12] The death of Philip\'s twin Jane six
        weeks after their birth, on January 26, 1929, profoundly affected Philip\'s life, leading to
        the recurrent motif of the \"phantom twin\" in his books.
        \n\tEarly writing\n\t
        Dick sold his first story, “Roog”, in 1951, about “a dog who imagined that the garbagemen
        who came every Friday morning were stealing valuable food which the family had carefully
        stored away in a safe metal container”,[17] and from then on wrote full-time. During 1952,
        his first speculative fiction publications appeared in July and September numbers of Planet
        Stories, edited by Jack O\'Sullivan, and in If and The Magazine of Fantasy and Science
        Fiction that year. His debut novel was Solar Lottery, published in 1955 as half of
        Ace Double #D-103 alongside The Big Jump by Leigh Brackett. The 1950s were a difficult
        and impoverished time for Dick, who once lamented, \"We couldn\'t even pay the late fees on
        a library book.\" He published almost exclusively within the science fiction genre,
        but dreamed of a career in mainstream fiction.[19] During the 1950s, he produced a series
        of non-genre, relatively conventional novels. In 1960, he wrote that he was willing to
        \"take twenty to thirty years to succeed as a literary writer\". The dream of mainstream
        success formally died in January 1963 when the Scott Meredith Literary Agency returned all
        of his unsold mainstream novels. Only one of these works, Confessions of a Crap Artist,
        was published during Dick\'s lifetime.
        \n\tIn 1963, Dick won the Hugo Award for The Man in the High Castle. Although he was hailed
        as a genius in the science fiction world, the mainstream literary world was unappreciative,
        and he could publish books only through low-paying science fiction publishers such as Ace.
        Even in his later years, he continued to have financial troubles. In the introduction to
        the 1980 short story collection The Golden Man, Dick wrote:
        \n\n\tSeveral years ago, when I was ill, Heinlein offered his help, anything he could do,
        and we had never met; he would phone me to cheer me up and see how I was doing. He wanted
        to buy me an electric typewriter, God bless him—one of the few true gentlemen in this
        world. I don\'t agree with any ideas he puts forth in his writing, but that is neither here
        nor there. One time when I owed the IRS a lot of money and couldn\'t raise it, Heinlein
        loaned the money to me. I think a great deal of him and his wife; I dedicated a book to
        them in appreciation. Robert Heinlein is a fine-looking man, very impressive and very
        military in stance; you can tell he has a military background, even to the haircut. He knows
        I\'m a flipped-out freak and still he helped me and my wife when we were in trouble. That is
        the best in humanity, there; that is who and what I love.
        \n\n\tFlight to Canada and suicide attempt
        \n\tIn 1971, Dick\'s marriage to Nancy Hackett broke down, and she moved out of their house
        in Santa Venetia, California. Having abused amphetamine for much of the past decade
        (stemming in part from his need to maintain a prolific writing regimen due to the financial
        exigencies of the science fiction field), he allowed other drug users to move into the
        house. Following the release of 21 novels between 1960 and 1970, these developments were
        exacerbated by unprecedented periods of writer\'s block, with Dick ultimately failing to
        publish new fiction until 1974.
        \n\tOne day in November, Dick returned to his home to discover that it had been burglarized,
        with his safe blown open and personal papers missing. The police were unable to determine
        the culprit, and even suspected Dick of having done it himself. Shortly afterwards,
        he was invited to be guest of honor at the Vancouver Science Fiction Convention in February
        1972. Within a day of arriving at the conference and giving his speech The Android and the
        Human, he informed people that he had fallen in love with a woman named Janis whom he had
        met there and announced that he would be remaining in Vancouver. An attendee of the
        conference, Michael Walsh, movie critic for local newspaper The Province, invited Dick to
        stay in his home, but asked him to leave two weeks later due to his erratic behavior.
        This was followed by Janis ending her and Dick\'s relationship and moving away. On March 23,
        1972, Dick attempted suicide by taking an overdose of the sedative potassium bromide.
        Subsequently, after deciding to seek help, Dick became a participant in X-Kalay (a Canadian
        Synanon-type recovery program), and was well enough by April to return to California.
        \n\tUpon relocating to Orange County, California at the behest of California State
        University, Fullerton professor Willis McNelly (who initiated a correspondence with Dick
        during his X-Kalay stint), he donated manuscripts, papers and other materials to the
        University\'s Special Collections Library, where they are archived in the Philip K. Dick
        Science Fiction Collection in the Pollak Library. During this period, Dick befriended a
        circle of Fullerton State students that encompassed several aspiring science fiction
        writers, including K. W. Jeter, James Blaylock and Tim Powers.
        \n\tDick returned to the events of these months while writing his 1977 novel A Scanner
        Darkly,which contains fictionalized depictions of the burglary of his home, his time using
        amphetamines and living with addicts, and his experiences of X-Kalay (portrayed in the novel
        as "New-Path"). A factual account of Dick\'s recovery program participation was portrayed
        in his posthumously released book The Dark Haired Girl, a collection of letters and journals
        from the period.
        \n\n\tParanormal experiences
        \n\tOn February 20, 1974, while recovering from the effects of sodium pentothal administered
        for the extraction of an impacted wisdom tooth, Dick received a home delivery of Darvon from
        a young woman. When he opened the door, he was struck by the beauty of the dark-haired girl
        and was especially drawn to her golden necklace. He asked her about its curious fish-shaped
        design. "This is a sign used by the early Christians," she said, and then left. Dick called
        the symbol the "vesicle pisces". This name seems to have been based on his conflation of two
        related symbols, the Christian ichthys symbol (two intersecting arcs delineating a fish in
        profile) which the woman was wearing, and the vesica piscis.
        \n\tDick recounted that as the sun glinted off the gold pendant, the reflection caused the
        generation of a "pink beam" of light that mesmerized him. He came to believe the beam
        imparted wisdom and clairvoyance, and also believed it to be intelligent. On one occasion,
        Dick was startled by a separate recurrence of the pink beam. It imparted the information to
        him that his infant son was ill. The Dicks rushed the child to the hospital, where his
        suspicion was confirmed by professional diagnosis.
        \n\tAfter the woman\'s departure, Dick began experiencing strange hallucinations. Although
        initially attributing them to side effects from medication, he considered this explanation
        implausible after weeks of continued hallucinations. "I experienced an invasion of my mind
        by a transcendentally rational mind, as if I had been insane all my life and suddenly I had
        become sane," Dick told Charles Platt.
        \n\tThroughout February and March 1974, Dick experienced a series of hallucinations, which
        he referred to as "2-3-74", shorthand for February–March 1974. Aside from the "pink beam",
        Dick described the initial hallucinations as geometric patterns, and, occasionally, brief
        pictures of Jesus and ancient Rome. As the hallucinations increased in length and frequency,
        Dick claimed he began to live two parallel lives, one as himself, "Philip K. Dick", and one
        as "Thomas", a Christian persecuted by Romans in the first century AD. He referred to the
        "transcendentally rational mind" as "Zebra", "God" and "VALIS". Dick wrote about the
        experiences, first in the semi-autobiographical novel Radio Free Albemuth and then in VALIS,
        The Divine Invasion and the unfinished The Owl in Daylight (the VALIS trilogy).
        \n\tIn 1974, Dick wrote a letter to the FBI, accusing various people, including University
        of California, San Diego professor Fredric Jameson, of being foreign agents of Warsaw Pact
        powers. He also wrote that Stanisław Lem was probably a false name used by a composite
        committee operating on orders of the Communist party to gain control over public opinion.
        \n\tAt one point, Dick felt that he had been taken over by the spirit of the prophet Elijah.
        He believed that an episode in his novel Flow My Tears, the Policeman Said was a detailed
        retelling of a biblical story from the Book of Acts, which he had never read. Dick
        documented and discussed his experiences and faith in a private journal he called his
        "exegesis", portions of which were later published as The Exegesis of Philip K. Dick. The
        last novel Dick wrote was The Transmigration of Timothy Archer; it was published shortly
        after his death in 1982.
        \n\n\tPersonal life
        \n\tDick was married five times:
        \n\t\t- Jeanette Marlin (May to November 1948)
        \n\t\t- Kleo Apostolides (June 14, 1950 to 1959)
        \n\t\t- Anne Williams Rubinstein (April 1, 1959 to October 1965)
        \n\t\t- Nancy Hackett (July 6, 1966 to 1972)
        \n\t\t- Leslie "Tessa" Busby (April 18, 1973 to 1977)
        \n\tDick had three children, Laura Archer Dick (born February 25, 1960 to Dick and his third
        wife, Anne Williams Rubenstein), Isolde Freya Dick (now Isa Dick Hackett) (born March 15,
        1967 to Dick and his fourth wife, Nancy Hackett), and Christopher Kenneth Dick (born July
        25, 1973 to Dick and his fifth wife, Leslie "Tessa" Busby).
        \n\tIn 1955, he and his second wife, Kleo Apostolides, received a visit from the FBI, which
        they believed to be the result of Kleo\'s socialist views and left-wing activities. The couple
        briefly befriended one of the FBI agents.
        \n\tHe was physically abusive with his third wife, Anne Williams Rubinstein; after one
        argument in 1963, he attempted to push her off a cliff in a car, then later claimed she was
        trying to kill him, and convinced a psychiatrist to commit her involuntarily. After filing
        for divorce in 1964, he moved to Oakland to live with a fan, Grania Davis. Shortly after,
        he attempted suicide by driving off the road while she was a passenger.
        \n\tDick tried to stay out of the political scene because of high societal turmoil from the
        Vietnam War. Still, he did show some anti-Vietnam War and anti-governmental sentiments. In
        1968, he joined the "Writers and Editors War Tax Protest",[15][31] an anti-war pledge to pay
        no U.S. federal income tax, which resulted in the confiscation of his car by the IRS.
        \n\n\tDeath
        \n\tOn February 17, 1982, after completing an interview, Dick contacted his therapist,
        complaining of failing eyesight, and was advised to go to a hospital immediately, but did
        not. The following day, he was found unconscious on the floor of his Santa Ana, California,
        home, having suffered a stroke. On February 25, Dick suffered another stroke in the hospital,
        which led to brain death. Five days later, on March 2, he was disconnected from life support
        and died. After his death, Dick\'s father, Joseph, took his son\'s ashes to Riverside
        Cemetery in Fort Morgan, Colorado, (section K, block 1, lot 56), where they were buried next
        to his twin sister Jane, who died in infancy. Her tombstone had been inscribed with both of
        their names at the time of her death, 53 years earlier.[32][33] He died months before the
        release of the first Blade Runner film.
    </string>

    <string name="books">
        \tDick\'s stories typically focus on the fragile nature of what is real and the construction
        of personal identity. His stories often become surreal fantasies, as the main characters
        slowly discover that their everyday world is actually an illusion assembled by powerful
        external entities, such as the suspended animation in Ubik,[35] vast political conspiracies
        or the vicissitudes of an unreliable narrator. "All of his work starts with the basic
        assumption that there cannot be one, single, objective reality", writes science fiction
        author Charles Platt. "Everything is a matter of perception. The ground is liable to shift
        under your feet. A protagonist may find himself living out another person\'s dream, or he
        may enter a drug-induced state that actually makes better sense than the real world, or he
        may cross into a different universe completely."
        \n\tAlternate universes and simulacra are common plot devices, with fictional worlds
        inhabited by common, working people, rather than galactic elites. "There are no heroes in
        Dick\'s books", Ursula K. Le Guin wrote, "but there are heroics. One is reminded of Dickens:
        what counts is the honesty, constancy, kindness and patience of ordinary people." Dick made
        no secret that much of his thinking and work was heavily influenced by the writings of Carl
        Jung. The Jungian constructs and models that most concerned Dick seem to be the archetypes
        of the collective unconscious, group projection/hallucination, synchronicities, and
        personality theory.[32] Many of Dick\'s protagonists overtly analyze reality and their
        perceptions in Jungian terms (see Lies Inc.).
        \n\tDick identified one major theme of his work as the question, "What constitutes the
        authentic human being?"[37] In works such as Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?, beings
        can appear totally human in every respect while lacking soul or compassion, while completely
        alien beings such as Glimmung in Galactic Pot-Healer may be more humane and complex than
        their human peers.
        \n\tMental illness was a constant interest of Dick\'s, and themes of mental illness permeate
        his work. The character Jack Bohlen in the 1964 novel Martian Time-Slip is an
        "ex-schizophrenic". The novel Clans of the Alphane Moon centers on an entire society made
        up of descendants of lunatic asylum inmates. In 1965, he wrote the essay titled
        "Schizophrenia and the Book of Changes".
        \n\tDrug use (including religious, recreational, and abuse) was also a theme in many of
        Dick\'s works, such as A Scanner Darkly and The Three Stigmata of Palmer Eldritch. Dick
        himself was a drug user for much of his life. According to a 1975 interview in Rolling Stone,
        Dick wrote all of his books published before 1970 while on amphetamines. "A Scanner Darkly
        (1977) was the first complete novel I had written without speed", said Dick in the interview.
        He also experimented briefly with psychedelics, but wrote The Three Stigmata of Palmer
        Eldritch, which Rolling Stone dubs "the classic LSD novel of all time", before he had ever
        tried them. Despite his heavy amphetamine use, however, Dick later said that doctors told
        him the amphetamines never actually affected him, that his liver had processed them before
        they reached his brain.
        \n\tSumming up all these themes in Understanding Philip K. Dick, Eric Carl Link discussed
        eight themes or \'ideas and motifs\': Epistemology and the Nature of Reality, Know Thyself,
        The Android and the Human, Entropy and Pot Healing, The Theodicy Problem, Warfare and Power
        Politics, The Evolved Human, and \'Technology, Media, Drugs and Madness\'.
        \n\n\tPen names
        \n\tDick had two professional stories published under the pen names Richard Phillipps and
        Jack Dowland. "Some Kinds of Life" was published in October 1953 in Fantastic Universe under
        byline Richard Phillipps, apparently because the magazine had a policy against publishing
        multiple stories by the same author in the same issue; "Planet for Transients" was published
        in the same issue under his own name.
        \n\tThe short story "Orpheus with Clay Feet" was published under the pen name Jack Dowland.
        The protagonist desires to be the muse for fictional author Jack Dowland, considered the
        greatest science fiction author of the 20th century. In the story, Dowland publishes a short
        story titled "Orpheus with Clay Feet" under the pen name Philip K. Dick.
        \n\tThe surname Dowland refers to Renaissance composer John Dowland, who is featured in
        several works. The title Flow My Tears, the Policeman Said directly refers to Dowland\'s
        best-known composition, "Flow My Tears". In the novel The Divine Invasion, the character
        Linda Fox, created specifically with Linda Ronstadt in mind, is an intergalactically famous
        singer whose entire body of work consists of recordings of John Dowland compositions.
        \n\n\tSelected works
        \n\tThe Man in the High Castle (1962) is set in an alternate history in which the United
        States is ruled by the victorious Axis powers. It is the only Dick novel to win a Hugo Award.
        In 2015 this was adapted into a television series by Amazon Studios.
        \n\tThe Three Stigmata of Palmer Eldritch (1965) utilizes an array of science fiction concepts
        and features several layers of reality and unreality. It is also one of Dick\'s first works
        to explore religious themes. The novel takes place in the 21st century, when, under UN
        authority, mankind has colonized the Solar System\'s every habitable planet and moon. Life
        is physically daunting and psychologically monotonous for most colonists, so the UN must
        draft people to go to the colonies. Most entertain themselves using \"Perky Pat\" dolls and
        accessories manufactured by Earth-based "P.P. Layouts". The company also secretly creates
        "Can-D", an illegal but widely available hallucinogenic drug allowing the user to
        "translate" into Perky Pat (if the drug user is a woman) or Pat\'s boyfriend, Walt (if the
        drug user is a man). This recreational use of Can-D allows colonists to experience a few
        minutes of an idealized life on Earth by participating in a collective hallucination.
        \n\tDo Androids Dream of Electric Sheep? (1968) is the story of a bounty hunter policing the
        local android population. It occurs on a dying, poisoned Earth de-populated of almost all
        animals and all "successful" humans; the only remaining inhabitants of the planet are people
        with no prospects off-world. The 1968 novel is the literary source of the film Blade Runner
        (1982). It is both a conflation and an intensification of the pivotally Dickian question:
        What is real, what is fake? What crucial factor defines humanity as distinctly "alive",
        versus those merely alive only in their outward appearance?
        \n\tUbik (1969) employs extensive psychic telepathy and a suspended state after death in
        creating a state of eroding reality. A group of psychics is sent to investigate a rival
        organisation, but several of them are apparently killed by a saboteur\'s bomb. Much of the
        following novel flicks between different equally plausible realities and the "real" reality,
        a state of half-life and psychically manipulated realities. In 2005, Time magazine listed it
        among the "All-TIME 100 Greatest Novels" published since 1923.
        \n\tFlow My Tears, the Policeman Said (1974) concerns Jason Taverner, a television star
        living in a dystopian near-future police state. After being attacked by an angry
        ex-girlfriend, Taverner awakens in a dingy Los Angeles hotel room. He still has his money
        in his wallet, but his identification cards are missing. This is no minor inconvenience,
        as security checkpoints (manned by "pols" and "nats", the police and National Guard) are
        set up throughout the city to stop and arrest anyone without valid ID. Jason at first thinks
        that he was robbed, but soon discovers that his entire identity has been erased. There is no
        record of him in any official database, and even his closest associates do not recognize or
        remember him. For the first time in many years, Jason has no fame or reputation to rely on.
        He has only his innate charm and social graces to help him as he tries to find out what
        happened to his past while avoiding the attention of the pols. The novel was Dick\'s first
        published novel after years of silence, during which time his critical reputation had grown,
        and this novel was awarded the John W. Campbell Memorial Award for Best Science Fiction
        Novel. It is the only Philip K. Dick novel nominated for both a Hugo and a Nebula Award.
        \n\tIn an essay written two years before his death, Dick described how he learned from his
        Episcopal priest that an important scene in Flow My Tears, the Policeman Said – involving
        its other main character, the eponymous Police General Felix Buckman, was very similar to a
        scene in Acts of the Apostles,[28] a book of the New Testament. Film director Richard
        Linklater discusses this novel in his film Waking Life, which begins with a scene reminiscent
        of another Dick novel, Time Out of Joint.
        \n\t\"A Scanner Darkly\" (1977) is a bleak mixture of science fiction and police procedural
        novels; in its story, an undercover narcotics police detective begins to lose touch with
        reality after falling victim to the same permanently mind-altering drug, Substance D, he
        was enlisted to help fight. Substance D is instantly addictive, beginning with a pleasant
        euphoria which is quickly replaced with increasing confusion, hallucinations and eventually
        total psychosis. In this novel, as with all Dick novels, there is an underlying thread of
        paranoia and dissociation with multiple realities perceived simultaneously. It was adapted
        to film by Richard Linklater.
        \n\tThe Philip K. Dick Reader is an introduction to the variety of Dick\'s short fiction.
        \"VALIS\" (1980) is perhaps Dick\'s most postmodern and autobiographical novel, examining his
        own unexplained experiences. It may also be his most academically studied work, and was
        adapted as an opera by Tod Machover.[45] Later works like the VALIS trilogy were heavily
        autobiographical, many with "two-three-seventy-four" (2-3-74) references and influences.
        The word VALIS is the acronym for Vast Active Living Intelligence System. Later,
        Dick theorized that VALIS was both a "reality generator" and a means of extraterrestrial
        communication. A fourth VALIS manuscript, Radio Free Albemuth, although composed in 1976,
        was posthumously published in 1985. This work is described by the publisher (Arbor House)
        as "an introduction and key to his magnificent VALIS trilogy".
        \n\tRegardless of the feeling that he was somehow experiencing a divine communication, Dick
        was never fully able to rationalize the events. For the rest of his life, he struggled to
        comprehend what was occurring, questioning his own sanity and perception of reality. He
        transcribed what thoughts he could into an eight-thousand-page, one-million-word journal
        dubbed the Exegesis. From 1974 until his death in 1982, Dick spent many nights writing in
        this journal. A recurring theme in Exegesis is Dick\'s hypothesis that history had been
        stopped in the first century AD, and that "the Empire never ended". He saw Rome as the
        pinnacle of materialism and despotism, which, after forcing the Gnostics underground, had
        kept the population of Earth enslaved to worldly possessions. Dick believed that VALIS had
        communicated with him, and anonymously others, to induce the impeachment of U.S. President
        Richard Nixon, whom Dick believed to be the current Emperor of Rome incarnate.
        \n\tIn a 1968 essay titled \"Self Portrait\", collected in the 1995 book The Shifting Realities
        of Philip K. Dick, Dick reflects on his work and lists which books he feels \"might escape
        World War Three\": Eye in the Sky, The Man in the High Castle, Martian Time-Slip,
        Dr. Bloodmoney, or How We Got Along After the Bomb, The Zap Gun, The Penultimate Truth,
        The Simulacra, The Three Stigmata of Palmer Eldritch (which he refers to as "the most vital
        of them all"), Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?, and Ubik. In a 1976 interview,
        Dick cited A Scanner Darkly as his best work, feeling that he "had finally written a true
        masterpiece, after 25 years of writing".
        \n\tIn the 1973 science fiction short story, \"The Pre-persons\", he criticizes American
        pro-abortion law.
    </string>

    <string name="movies">
        \n\tSeveral of Dick\'s stories have been made into films. Dick himself wrote a screenplay
        for an intended film adaptation of Ubik in 1974, but the film was never made. Many film
        adaptations have not used Dick\'s original titles. When asked why this was, Dick\'s ex-wife
        Tessa said, "Actually, the books rarely carry Phil's original titles, as the editors usually
        wrote new titles after reading his manuscripts. Phil often commented that he couldn\'t write
        good titles. If he could, he would have been an advertising writer instead of a novelist."
        Films based on Dick\'s writing had accumulated a total revenue of over US $1 billion by 2009.
        \n\tBlade Runner (1982), based on Dick\'s 1968 novel Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?,
        directed by Ridley Scott and starring Harrison Ford and Rutger Hauer. A screenplay had been
        in the works for years before Scott took the helm, with Dick being extremely critical of all
        versions. Dick was still apprehensive about how his story would be adapted for the film when
        the project was finally put into motion. Among other things, he refused to do a novelization
        of the film. But contrary to his initial reactions, when he was given an opportunity to see
        some of the special effects sequences of Los Angeles 2019, Dick was amazed that the
        environment was "exactly as how I\'d imagined it!", though Ridley Scott has mentioned he had
        never even read the source material. Following the screening, Dick and Scott had a frank
        but cordial discussion of Blade Runner\'s themes and characters, and although they had
        wildly differing views, Dick fully backed the film from then on, stating that his "life and
        creative work are justified and completed by Blade Runner".[51] Dick died from a stroke less
        than four months before the release of the film.
        \n\tTotal Recall (1990), based on the short story "We Can Remember It for You Wholesale",
        directed by Paul Verhoeven and starring Arnold Schwarzenegger.
        \n\tConfessions d\'un Barjo (1992), titled Barjo in its English-language release, a French
        film based on the non-science-fiction novel Confessions of a Crap Artist.
        \n\tScreamers (1995), based on the short story "Second Variety", directed by Christian
        Duguay and starring Peter Weller. The location was altered from a war-devastated Earth to a
        distant planet. A sequel, titled Screamers: The Hunting, was released straight to DVD in 2009.
        \n\tMinority Report (2002), based on the short story "The Minority Report", directed by
        Steven Spielberg and starring Tom Cruise.
        \n\tImpostor (2002), based on the 1953 story "Impostor," directed by Gary Fleder and
        starring Gary Sinise, Vincent D\'Onofrio and Madeleine Stowe. The story was also adapted in
        1962 for the British television anthology series Out of This World.
        \n\tPaycheck (2003), directed by John Woo and starring Ben Affleck, based on Dick\'s short
        story of the same name.
        \n\tA Scanner Darkly (2006), directed by Richard Linklater and starring Keanu Reeves, Winona
        Ryder, and Robert Downey Jr., based on Dick\'s novel of the same name. The film was produced
        using the process of rotoscoping: it was first shot in live-action and then the live footage
        was animated over.
        \n\tNext (2007), directed by Lee Tamahori and starring Nicolas Cage, loosely based on the
        short story "The Golden Man".
        \n\tRadio Free Albemuth (2010), directed by John Alan Simon loosely based on the novel Radio
        Free Albemuth.
        \n\tThe Adjustment Bureau (2011), directed by George Nolfi and starring Matt Damon, loosely
        based on the short story "Adjustment Team".
        \n\tTotal Recall (2012), directed by Len Wiseman and starring Colin Farrell, second film
        adaptation of the short story "We Can Remember It for You Wholesale".
        \n\tBlade Runner 2049 (2017), directed by Denis Villeneuve and starring Ryan Gosling and
        Harrison Ford, a sequel to the 1982 film Blade Runner, based on Do Androids Dream of
        Electric Sheep?.
        \n\tFuture films based on Dick\'s writing include an animated adaptation of The King of the
        Elves from Walt Disney Animation Studios, which was set to be released in the spring of
        2016 but is currently still in preproduction; and a film adaptation of Ubik which, according
        to Dick\'s daughter, Isa Dick Hackett, is in advanced negotiation.[52] Ubik was set to be
        made into a film by Michel Gondry.[53] In 2014, however, Gondry told French outlet Telerama
        (via Jeux Actu), that he was no longer working on the project.
        \n\tThe Terminator series prominently features the theme of humanoid assassination machines
        first portrayed in Second Variety. The Halcyon Company, known for developing the Terminator
        franchise, acquired right of first refusal to film adaptations of the works of Philip K.
        Dick in 2007. In May 2009, they announced plans for an adaptation of Flow My Tears, the
        Policeman Said.
    </string>



</resources>
